nicole o'bomsawin

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Passionate software developer with a primary focus in MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js (MERN Stack) in addition to front-end languages and frameworks. Experience collaborating on multiple web projects for small businesses and Fortune 500 global companies.

Atlanta, GA (518) 852-8019

nicoleobomsawin@gmail.com GitHub | LinkedIn | Website

SKILLS

React, JavaScript, SQL, Node, js, MongoDB, Express, Git, RESTful API, HTML5, CSS, jQuery

PROJECTS

QuizApp | https://git.io/JUkuF

A web application that authenticates each user upon login and allows them to take quizzes varying by subject and grade level. Once a quiz has been taken, data is sorted and shown on the leaderboard. **Built with:** MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, Passport

Employee Directory | https://git.io/JJA8r

An employee directory for managers. This application gives users the ability to view non-sensitive data about their employees, filter by first name or last name, or sort by employee ID. **Built with**: React, Node.js

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Certificate | August 2020 Georgia Institute of Technology

Immersive 6-month software development training program that covered the MERN stack. Included React, MongoDB, SQL and MySQL, Node.js, and Express.

BUSINESS & MARKETING

Bachelor of Science | December 2015 University at Albany (SUNY)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Modo Modo Agency | Atlanta, GA

Senior Account Executive

SEPTEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Built relationships with key clients to facilitate and help grow business.
- Helped create and maintain project timelines, making sure to adjust client and project management team
 expectations as necessary.
- Wrote creative briefs and assisted in kick-off meetings with strategy and creative for key, enterprise-level clients.

Overit Media | Albany, NY

Account Manager

APRIL 2018 - AUGUST 2019

- Worked alongside the COO to provide strategic marketing and digital campaigns for local and global clients.
- Managed budgets and billing for over \$800k in revenue.
- Created, presented, and helped execute strategies for campaign frameworks and creative concepts.

Bluesail Marketing | Poughkeepsie, NY

Co-Founder, Designer & Developer

APRIL 2018 - AUGUST 2019

- Designed and developed custom WordPress templates to align with each client's needs.
- Utilized Bootstrap UI framework and front-end languages like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Potratz Advertising | Schenectady, NY

Marketing Communications Manager

NOVEMBER 2016 - JUNE 2017

- Oversaw and helped create a custom Facebook Messenger bot utilizing Facebook developer tools.
- Wrote and polished content for a new product launch.
- Assisted in the creation and execution of a digital strategy to increase new product sales.

Social Media & PR Specialist

MARCH 2016 - NOVEMBER 2016

- Created and posted content for multiple social media platforms.
- Wrote short-form blogs and scripts for internal videos.